CURRICULUM VITAE



Full stack web developer and an analytical problem solver with a background in chemistry and biology. My work experiences include research, teaching, sales and analyzing data. I have a keen interest in web design, technical design and analyzing data. I am experienced in HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, SQL, Matlab, R-Stat and Excel.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SERVICE TECHNICIAN – Metrohm Nordic AB

December 2016 - Present

Pre-maintenance and repair of laboratory equipment (e.g. IC, Titration, KF, Online instruments). Includes planning, administration and customer meetings. During my time at Metrohm Nordic I've been a part of translating material hazard data sheet from English to Swedish and also structured the handling and certification of test equipment.

LABORATORY ASSISTANT - Stockholm University

2016 - 2016 (less than one year)

Environmental monitoring of Baltic Sea and sampling of water chemistry and surveillance of biological parameters such as phytoplankton. I have also worked at an accredited laboratory where I processed samples, measured oxygen content and controlled the pH of water.

LICENTIATE IN ECOLOGY – Umeå University

2010 - 2015

Research connected with analysing how nutrients influence lake ecosystem. Within my research have implemented empirical studies, processed samples at laboratory and conducted statistical analysis. I have also created theoretical food webs models in Matlab. Within my research I also have had responsibilities to teach and educate student within nature science.

SALES MANAGER - Predect AB

2010 – 2010 (one year)

Product responsibility for online-sensors used within the water industry. I was accountable for the development of a customer base of approximately 50 customers, and created prospectuses and sales.

SALES ENGINEER - Cerlic Control AB

2008 – 2009 (one year)

Sales with a focus on optimization of processes in municipal treatment plants, paper-pulp industry and chemical industry. I had region responsibility with 2-3 travel days/week, mainly in southern and central Sweden. It also included the planning, follow-up and execution of customer visits. Results was reported and followed in administrative systems.

ANALYTIC CHEMIST – Coca Cola Enterprises

2002 - 2002 (less than one year)

Quality analysis of process water and of finished products such as Coke and Sprite. Included elements such as HPLC, spectroscopy, titration, conductivity measurement and microbial analyses.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Developer, 2020 – 2021

Code Institute, Scotland

Master, Ecotoxicology, 2000 – 2006

Uppsala University, Sweden

Bachelor, Chemical Engineering, 2000 - 2006

Uppsala University, Sweden

Exchange Studies, Natural Science, 2003 – 2004

University of Victoria, Canada

GUSTAF THOMSSON

Horngatan 153

117 34 Stockholm

+46 (0) 734026191

gustafthomsson@hotmail.com